<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>teotoplak.com</title>
    <link>https://teotoplak.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on teotoplak.com</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://teotoplak.com/resources/toplak.jpeg</url>
      <link>https://teotoplak.com/resources/toplak.jpeg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 20:46:35 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://teotoplak.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Optimise for Job to Be Done</title>
      <link>https://teotoplak.com/posts/optimise-for-job-to-be-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 20:46:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teotoplak.com/posts/optimise-for-job-to-be-done/</guid>
      <description>Technology is the way we do things; it is a technique. When new technology arises, a better way of doing things has been created.
The combustion engines created a better way of going from point A to B compared to horses. Telephones created a better way to communicate with other people over long distances compared to post mail.
Many tech companies tend not to be aware of what is that &amp;ldquo;thing&amp;rdquo; for which they are creating a better way of doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checklist for Evaluating Startup Ideas</title>
      <link>https://teotoplak.com/posts/checklist-for-evaluating-startup-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 23:00:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teotoplak.com/posts/checklist-for-evaluating-startup-ideas/</guid>
      <description>This is my checklist for evaluating startup ideas. It also helps you define the most important aspects of an early startup business.
I consider a startup an organization that is creating a scalable service or a product in conditions of extreme uncertainty. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend this checklist for other types of businesses.
Pitch Creating a pitch is a forcing function for achieving clarity about an idea. In this case a good pitch contains less than 50 characters, defines well what you&amp;rsquo;re building (product), and for whom you&amp;rsquo;re building (customer).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My life-long career goal</title>
      <link>https://teotoplak.com/posts/my-life-long-career-goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 14:44:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teotoplak.com/posts/my-life-long-career-goal/</guid>
      <description>This post is about a life-long career goal I&amp;rsquo;m setting for myself.
The goal is: I will serve one million people with a net positive impact on the world in a personally sustainable way.
 A reachable goal is a clear goal. That is why I need to define this goal more clearly:
 By &amp;ldquo;serve&amp;rdquo; I mean producing value for people. One million can be a sum from multiple different services I provided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closing the Evolution Gap</title>
      <link>https://teotoplak.com/posts/closing-the-evolution-gap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 11:19:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teotoplak.com/posts/closing-the-evolution-gap/</guid>
      <description>The Evolution Gap Two hundred thousand years ago, Homo sapiens were walking with a relatively similar brain to one we currently have in our heads. If you would take a baby from thousands of years ago, it would grow indistinguishable from other people in present surroundings. Our brain physiology didn&amp;rsquo;t change much. But our environment changed drastically.
For example, in Homo Sapiens age you would need to make decisions about where and how to find food.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
